hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and in this podcast we
talk about ways for coaches mentors and
trainers to grow in their life and in
their business to make more money now
what I want to talk about today is
something that again comes up all the
time people ask me for and I like to do
a refresher of often is how to pick your
Niche or the topic that you want to uh
build a product around and it's because
we have so many different things that we
can do and so what I want to do is I
want to dive in real quick with you to
give you my blueprint for figuring out
what is the best Niche for your coaching
program your membership or your courses
here's one of the first things that we
want to decide is that if you have
trouble making decisions as to what to
pick that's going to be one of your root
issues if you're worried about picking
the wrong idea or it not working out the
way that you want it to um that's what
we need to address I made a lot of
people where they have as many ideas as
there are stars in the sky and they
struggle to be able to pick one idea let
alone decide if they should do anything
and so it's actually not that they can't
come up with ideas they don't know which
one is the right path to do because they
don't feel good enough about each idea
that they that they go on I struggle
with the same thing even when I have to
decide on what to record for this
podcast I'm like okay I could do this
topic I could do this topic but at the
end of the day we got to just pick one
idea something to put out there and and
and generally it's going to be whatever
is the first thing that subconsciously
in my intuition comes to the top of mind
or what is something that people have
been asking me about what is maybe
something that I haven't talked about in
a while when it comes to your business
though you might be like well I'm just
starting out I don't have a number of
different things I talk about so how can
I pick one thing if I can do all of
these things okay understand this here's
why we want to pick something for our
marketing is because when we're
marketing our business people they might
be multi-dimensional they might have all
these different things that they can do
but without being consistent and
specific there's no direction that
people can go in and that turns into
zero sales and zero results in our
business so when you're attracting
people into your business you want
something that is specific for people to
choose as a starting place to work with
you now you might say well are there
better ideas than others and I'm not
sure which one is the best and see
that's the hamster wheel Loop that we
want to that we get on that we got to
get off of and we got to pick one idea
start from there and then keep moving
things forward
I can tell you this is that the number
one reason why a lot of coaches and
mentors struggle is because they're not
picking something and they're worried
about it not being right and them
picking the wrong idea or missing out on
opportunities and that right there is
something that we need to resolve inside
of ourselves and so I I tell people this
is you know go for a walk breathe
through it calm your nervous system down
and see what does your inner voice say
as far as one of those ideas goes now if
you're struggling to hear any any ideas
or come up with any ideas I love to use
AI to help me with this and so you can
use chat GPT which you can get a free
account with over at chat gp.com and
start to brainstorm some ideas when it
comes to Niche and and if you're not
doing this you're really missing out
because the it's just it's so good for
you to be able to do this and I'm going
to show you why that is so watch this I
am a coach who wants to start a coaching
program um
um I'm in the health space can you give
me 100 possible niches to start with to
Market a program in this space okay I
misspelled what I type but that's okay
it doesn't matter and so what it's going
to do is it's going to it's going to
give us 20 different starting places in
that Health idea maybe you don't even
know you're like well I don't even know
if I can do Health okay so here's what
we want to do is we want to decide what
are the areas that maybe you have
expertise in what do you know that might
be better than somebody else that might
that you might know more than other
people that are out there there might be
other people in the world today that
they don't know as much as you about a
certain topic and usually it's going to
be based on an area of experience or
expertise that you've spent years and
years and years on you know I I I meet
people all the time they tell me I don't
even have a niche or a topic and then I
talk to them they've been doing the same
thing in their career like creating
curriculum for schools for 40 years and
and yet for some reason they think that
that that that's not marketable and I'm
like hello that's amazing that's
incredible and so picking even one thing
that you do have experience in maybe you
don't think it's important enough but
realize that that the value that you
have put in the the the grind that you
have put in to learn your expertise over
the years is valuable to somebody else
and it's something that you can choose
from now here's the other thing too
maybe you're like well I don't want to
do that cuz somebody else does is that
maybe you you don't want you want to be
original you don't want to be like
somebody else who's out there on the
internet can I can I can can I give you
a little bit of a reality check here
every single Niche possible has been
done by somebody else um and it's
actually better to not try to find
something that nobody has ever done uh
period and so that's okay that somebody
else has done that they're not you and
so you get to stand out because you are
you and so one of the other things that
I encourage people to do is maybe pick
the top three ideas maybe you want to
help men with their mental health and
physical fitness and you want to do so
in the form of a retreat or something
like that literally you could bring all
of that together into your Niche and you
could combine those into one package as
far as that goes now listen if you're
still stuck you have no idea what you
could do check this out here's another
chat gbt prompt that you could do I want
to start a coaching business and have no
idea what I could do give me a 100 ideas
for or Niche or topic I could start with
to
brainstorm career coaching leadership
coaching life coaching business coaching
startup small business time management
health and fitness relationship marriage
parenting academic conflict resolution
investment
coaching uh creativity coaching writing
coaching Style coaching and then you
might be like well I want to make a
membership okay great awesome watch can
you adjust these for a membership based
monthly program okay here's 100 niches
for a monthly program career advancement
membership executive success membership
productivity membership health and
wellness club relationship enrichment
academic success stressfree living debt
management membership personal branding
creativity writing YouTube growth inter
Your Design real
estate okay so you can see like there
are ideas that you could pick something
from these ideas and start with and and
run with as far as that goes okay let's
pick this one right here travel
Enthusiast membership okay take the
niche and this is something that I want
you to do by the way once you pick an
idea you want to dive deeper into 100
subtopics sub niches and generate 100
sub Niche
subtopics around this topic
okay solo travel tips coup's travel
guides Family Travel Adventure travel
travel blogging travel writing see so
these are
subcategories to any of the niches so
literally there's there's a potential
just off of chat GPT alone if you find
sub niches from every single one of
these over thousand ideas that you could
pick from that you could choose could be
an idea for you to pick a niche from
okay and so I would recommend playing
around with chat GPT and and doing
something like this traveling for yoga
retreats can you find me a 100 sub
niches around and you could literally go
a third layer and you could find 10,000
or 100,000 ideas I think it' be 100,000
ideas look at this each sub Niche could
have own sub niches okay in specific
areas of the world or things like that
this might be a little too sub niche as
far as this goes but you could combine
like a bunch of these into one so this
could be like the foundation of your
program right here that's the topic that
you're going to do so now map out a
coaching program with 12 months of
training modules based on and then you
can copy and paste the idea that it
gives you and then watch it's going to
to map out 12 months of
modules introduction luxury and budget
yoga retreats specialized demographic
Retreats thematic yoga retreats wellness
and healing Adventure activity specific
location okay so the idea could be like
a membership that you could host based
around like yoga retreats or things like
that and and you could literally break
this down based on this watch this
okay I want to coach women on painfree
birth give me 100 subtopics I could use
and then turn that into a 12
month program
outline for a
yearlong coaching program see so if
you're like I don't have enough ideas to
talk about I guarantee you that using
chat GPT can can unlock a bunch of ideas
in your mind that you could use to be
able to come up with idea like this is
an incredible amount of ideas related to
birth and pregnancy right here that
could either be modules mini trainings
YouTube videos things like that okay so
if we go a little bit deeper watch
this okay it's generating a 100 of those
now it's going to map out a 12mth
program introduction Mind and Body
Connection Stress Management breathing
natural pain management parental care
techniques birth planning birth
environment specific techniques
preparing
physically and some of you are like I
don't know what I would talk about in a
presentation for an hour or a video or a
training or a course and right here this
gives you ideas based on that okay turn
this into a eight module course based on
the
above
okay and there you go understanding
painfree birth mind Body Connection so
literally
like based on just what like two prompts
in chat GPT I just you can come up with
any idea a Year's worth of content a
starting place to choose from now again
you're going to have to make a decision
you're going to have to decide and and
if you're struggling to make a decision
again those are going to be more
internal battles internally in your mind
in your spirit in your heart that you're
going to want to work through and that's
where we want to find out what are we
trying to avoid what do we not want to
happen what are we afraid might go wrong
what risks are there and really dive
deeper into that as far as that goes and
so that's that's going to ultimately be
if you use these tactics to find your
Niche you still haven't decided it's
going to be something else
subconsciously is why and that's where
we want to address and where we want to
look and chat GPT can help you with that
as well watch this check this out
I'm struggling to decide on a niche in
my business I I
have watch
this this is going to be
great I'm struggling to decide on a
niche in my business I have all the
following ideas but I'm struggling to
pick one and get started act as an
expert in helping people who struggle to
decide from a
mindset standpoint and give me some
tactics here's my ideas below and I can
paste the ideas below and then I can I
can basically have it say Okay
strategies for choosing Clarity of
vision visualize the success overcoming
perfectionism Embrace imperfection build
confidence and trust yourself start
doing market research find F feedback
and validate it look at where your
strengths and weaknesses and
opportunities are okay dive deep into
what the market needs are find an expert
find a coach that can help you with that
connect with other Professionals in the
space um initial offering maybe a
condensed version of one module list out
the pros and cons prioritize based on
impact and feasibility set a clear
criteria make a timed decision to break
out of analysis paralysis and then uh
can you give me more insight on on why I
would have a fear of missing out
struggle to decide or not making a
decision based on mindset and mental
health angle okay so watch this
certainly fear of missing out struggle
to make decisions particularly in your
Niche can be a reason for uh having high
standards of perfection fear of making
mistakes the sheer volume of information
can be overwhelming you have multiple
interests you don't want to have regret
you fear the uncertainty maybe you're
comparing to others you have self-doubt
you're too focused on the outcome you're
too attached to the
outcome okay so accept imperfection stay
present in the moment this is so
powerful limit the amount of information
you're taking in start to trust yourself
more visualize more small steps
experimentation start journaling
mindfulness cognitive behavioral
techniques such as psychology and mental
health and things like that okay and so
this is great and by the way chat GPT
can help you with even a lot of the
mental aspects of this you can even say
act as an expert in the mental health
aspect of the above and ask me some
questions to dive deeper and give me a
breakthrough okay and by the way if
you're a coach who helps other people
with this type of stuff as well you can
even work with people through this type
of stuff and ask these questions and
even have chat jbt help be a guide to
you to help people you know these are
questions to ask yourself why does a
perfect decision look like how realistic
is this standard how do you feel about
when you make a mistake or is it
something that doesn't go as planned how
do you typically feel when faced with
multiple decisions what strategies have
you found to break past overwhelm what
specific fears do you have about
choosing the wrong Niche can you recall
a time when you made a decision and
later regretted it and how you handled
that situation so literally like chat
gbt can not only help you decide in your
Niche but it can help you get to the
root cause of why you're not making a
decision and if you can get to that root
cause and then you start to gain the
courage to take action to get the help
to get the support to work with a
trusted Mentor like myself to help you
move past that and then start to take
action and you start to build your
course and you build your membership and
you build your coaching program to get
the success that you want you can become
Unstoppable and Achieve what seems
impossible is no longer impossible and
it's actually very tangible
realistic and simple for you and AI can
be a powerful tool for breaking you out
of that trap or that struggle of not
knowing what decision to make and I'm so
thankful that we have it in our Arsenal
today we didn't have this a couple years
ago and so now like the idea of
struggling with Niche no longer needs to
be an issue when you have ai or you have
mentors like myself to be able to guide
you on these topics listen if you listen
to this podcast maybe you're struggling
with Niche you're struggling to decide
on how to pick a niche let me know in
the comments below maybe what some of
those reasons might be and I'd love to
comment back to you and maybe see if I
can come up with some solutions as well
all right grow your life everybody and
we'll talk soon have a good one
[Music]